<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://nzge.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://nzge.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-05-01T00:47:08+00:00</updated><id>https://nzge.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">My Website</title><subtitle>my personal website</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Creative spill</title><link href="https://nzge.github.io/2025/04/30/Creative-Spill.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Creative spill" /><published>2025-04-30T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-04-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://nzge.github.io/2025/04/30/Creative%20Spill</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nzge.github.io/2025/04/30/Creative-Spill.html">&lt;p&gt;What is “creative spill” and how do we harness it?&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>nzge</name></author><summary type="html">What is “creative spill” and how do we harness it?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Inspiration</title><link href="https://nzge.github.io/2025/04/15/Inspiration.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Inspiration" /><published>2025-04-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-04-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://nzge.github.io/2025/04/15/Inspiration</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nzge.github.io/2025/04/15/Inspiration.html">&lt;p&gt;What inspires me?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is inspiration? Is it what drives us in our day to day action?
Is it what gets us out of bed?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Behind discipline (the moments where ) is there an underlying passion that drives our personal narrative. 
I have never found discipline to get me thorugh the day. If there is an action that I know to be good for me but I can’t convince myself on a spiritual level that it fundamentally contributes positively to who I am as a person, it is extremely hard for me to do it. I’m sure that isn’t an original thought. Maybe my understanding of discipline is completely miscontrued. 
But I always hear the most disciplined and successful people in the world, the David Goggins of the world, throw around the word/concept discipline as if this singular concept is what should drive us to perform the actions that we take. In my opinion the idea that that is what keeps us going is a bit reductive.
But at the same time, maybe life is not that complicated. We need simple words and concepts like “discipline” to drive us and push us. It is easy for our monkey brains to compute. A simple platitude to keep us from going insane.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>nzge</name></author><summary type="html">What inspires me?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Open source</title><link href="https://nzge.github.io/2025/04/10/Open-Source.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Open source" /><published>2025-04-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-04-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://nzge.github.io/2025/04/10/Open%20Source</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nzge.github.io/2025/04/10/Open-Source.html">&lt;p&gt;We stand on the backs of giants. Or maybe one metaphorical giant rather.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many current tools scrape/aggregate resources from across the web. Most egregious instances of this at the forefront of media are the various AI tools we use now on a daily basis.
Is this forgery/thievery or the next step in human evolution? That we as a singular race can levy the intellect of the entire human race, as one breathing unit? Open source on a global scale?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The power of open source as all-encompassing design/intellectual philosophy is one that favors an open collaboration with the world at large. An unselfish passing of information and material that doesn’t ask for any favors in return.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Does this promote homogeneity? The loss of self identity?&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>nzge</name></author><summary type="html">We stand on the backs of giants. Or maybe one metaphorical giant rather.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">First post</title><link href="https://nzge.github.io/2025/04/09/First-Post.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="First post" /><published>2025-04-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-04-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://nzge.github.io/2025/04/09/First%20Post</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nzge.github.io/2025/04/09/First-Post.html">&lt;p&gt;Hi. This is my first post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hello World.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;meep meep meep&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>nzge</name></author><summary type="html">Hi. This is my first post.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Test</title><link href="https://nzge.github.io/2025/03/06/Test.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Test" /><published>2025-03-06T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-03-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://nzge.github.io/2025/03/06/Test</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nzge.github.io/2025/03/06/Test.html">&lt;p&gt;A banana is an edible fruit – botanically a berry – produced by several
kinds of large herbaceous flowering plants in the genus Musa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In some countries, bananas used for cooking may be called “plantains”,
distinguishing them from dessert bananas. The fruit is variable in size,
color, and firmness, but is usually elongated and curved, with soft
flesh rich in starch covered with a rind, which may be green, yellow,
red, purple, or brown when ripe.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>nzge</name></author><summary type="html">A banana is an edible fruit – botanically a berry – produced by several kinds of large herbaceous flowering plants in the genus Musa.</summary></entry></feed>