<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-05-13T20:37:21-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">My Website</title><subtitle>my personal website</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Rpgs</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/05/10/RPGs.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Rpgs" /><published>2025-05-10T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2025-05-10T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/05/10/RPGs</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/05/10/RPGs.html">&lt;p&gt;The RPG genre just might be the video game genre to rule them all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other genres for the most part occupy a confined set of constraints (some of which have been artificially placed by market trends and what’s popular).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The RPG fantasy is one that appeals in a way to a mass audience. The fantasy of an alternate reality that you can live and breath.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the true potential of RPGs is so far from being realized. In execution RPGs is not even 20% of it’s maximum potential. The reason is that to create something as immersive as an RPG is probably one of the most labor intensive undertakings in the gaming sphere, I daresay in the world. The RPGs space is also very much plagued with invasive monetization schemes, probably because of how monetarily draining creating an RPG is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AI?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As much as it hurts to say, and as much as it may be taking a knife and stabbing it in the hearts of artisans of the craft of gamemaking, I believe the advent of AI is one crucial step to creating a truly immersive RPG experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we can place certain restriction on AI and give it guidelines, the possibilities are endless. For example, in terms of asset creation. If we train AI on human-crafted limbs and arms assets for example, AI can riff off of these creations, we place restrictions on how these assets can be used. Ai can then generate creatures based off of these assets.
Program a sort of modularity to AI generation, restricting AI to generate new things by fitting things together like lego blocks. Use AI as a RNG kind of deal but with some advanced intelligent capabilities to create things that are not just&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This philosophy can be applied to a variety of game assets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This isn’t some novel concept. Random generation of things is far from a new idea.
Take terrain generation in Minecraft for example.
AI can just take generation of things to a grander scale.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>nzge</name></author><summary type="html">The RPG genre just might be the video game genre to rule them all.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Brotherhood</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/05/05/Brotherhood.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Brotherhood" /><published>2025-05-05T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2025-05-05T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/05/05/Brotherhood</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/05/05/Brotherhood.html">&lt;p&gt;Brotherhood seems to be the perfect formula for succes and innovation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wright brothers. 
Coen brothers, Russo brothers,&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>nzge</name></author><summary type="html">Brotherhood seems to be the perfect formula for succes and innovation.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Student</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/05/02/Student.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Student" /><published>2025-05-02T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2025-05-02T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/05/02/Student</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/05/02/Student.html">&lt;p&gt;From this day forth, I declare myself a student of the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At heart, I am a romantic. Not in the colloquial sense, but more of a period sense, like the romantic period. There is a certain dreaminess and romance I choose to believe about the world.
I cannot live without it, even if it is a air of romance that I have fabricated in my mind. It exists to drive me and keep me same, to have a certain sense of hope for tomorrow, a greater tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>nzge</name></author><summary type="html">From this day forth, I declare myself a student of the world.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Design</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/05/01/Design.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Design" /><published>2025-05-01T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2025-05-01T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/05/01/Design</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/05/01/Design.html">&lt;p&gt;For most people, design is overlooked. 
But in fact, it shapes the world we live in. 
Design carries a utiliarian/functionalist aspect. But design even more importantly holds an aesthetic perspective/element.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel as if design is so grossly underlooked. The way people have intentionally added curves and lines to a table, chair, house, desk, poster, whatever, fundamentally shapes the mental image of what that object should look like in our minds. Design is powerful in that way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do we ever stop to think about why do things look the way they do?
Someone took the time out of their day, month, year, and thought about these things. Toiled over it. Made it their life mission.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/media/!blog/chair.png&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin: auto;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Woah. a chair.&lt;br /&gt;
The reason why we see chairs that look like this goddam everywhere, and why when we think of cheap plastic outdoor chair this image is seared into our mind is some absolute numbknuckle bozo (kidding actually quite brillaint) decided to recruit a few of his brain cells to conjure a nifty little concept of a stackable plastic chair.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is called the monobloc chair, a brilliant feat of engineering&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The wooden veneer has become almost a cultural staple of the late 20th century to early 21st century aesthetic. There are these small yet resoundingly poignant details that shape the visual essence/depiction/image of the world we live in today. These small little aesthetic metas ideas that persist and propagate, covering the entire visual landscape of a nation or world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also just learned that Champion invented the hoodie. Pretty neat.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>nzge</name></author><summary type="html">For most people, design is overlooked. But in fact, it shapes the world we live in. Design carries a utiliarian/functionalist aspect. But design even more importantly holds an aesthetic perspective/element.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Creative spill</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/04/30/Creative-Spill.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Creative spill" /><published>2025-04-30T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2025-04-30T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/04/30/Creative%20Spill</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/04/30/Creative-Spill.html">&lt;p&gt;What is “creative spill” and how do we harness it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes the flow is torrential. Sometimes it’s dry as a desert.
Creation is my therapy. 
Embrace the insanity, when you are in the zone and you want to do nothing else but the task at hand. Embrace the hyperfixation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone needs a canvas to fill. A page they can write on. 
A way to affirm they can exist.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>nzge</name></author><summary type="html">What is “creative spill” and how do we harness it?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Renaissance man</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/04/29/Renaissance-Man.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Renaissance man" /><published>2025-04-29T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2025-04-29T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/04/29/Renaissance%20Man</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/04/29/Renaissance-Man.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What does it mean to be a Renaissance man in 2025?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Does the Renaissance man spread their skill points across various talents/skills, instead of leveling and mastering one skill tree. Jack of all trades, master of none?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Does the Renaissance man have a place in the modern world? Does he hold relevancy? What is his role, or maybe is there one for him rather?&lt;/strong&gt; It seems more and more we are taught to pursue one thing only, put all our eggs in one basket. Let that one major you chooze on a whim in high school dictate the trajectory of your entire adult life. It could be a natural product of industrialization. We have becomes tiny ants in a larger colony network. We only need to take care of our own unique task, our own little cog in the greater engine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At one time, life was not so. Life persisted only on the condition that we have to tend to all our aspects of our life diligently. Not even talking from a survival perspective, tending to our food, our family, and building shelter, and such, is this true. Even as recent as the 1800s, our elected officials, the aristocratic, were not only politically inclined but students of science, math, and the arts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One might say that the traditional Japanese man is the antithesis of this philosophy. Shokunin 
Kishitsu, “the craftsman’s spirit.” A pursuit of perfection in one’s work, in one’s singular commitment to excellence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is the allure of being a Renaissance man?&lt;/strong&gt;
One may say that the Renaissance philosophy is one that leaves no stone unturned. To pursue the betterment of oneself, and perhaps even the world at large, from a completely holistic perspective?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some problems are solved from a multidisciplinary perspective, recruiting an eclectic approach to reason.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am at a crossroads. Perfect one, or pursue many? This question may encapsulate a broader perspective of existence, but it is one I ask myself (either consciously or subconsciously) everyday. Should I be spending all my time learning one thing or doing one thing today, or have a balanced day various things?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How to choose? Life is so short, that maybe the question holds no value. Why even ask? Maybe just do. As cliche as it maybe, perhaps we must follow the heart, the gentle heart (find the kind heart within and listen, and not the violent heart).&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>nzge</name></author><summary type="html">What does it mean to be a Renaissance man in 2025?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The seed</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/04/28/The-Seed.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The seed" /><published>2025-04-28T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2025-04-28T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/04/28/The%20Seed</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/04/28/The-Seed.html">&lt;p&gt;Why is the seed such a powerful metaphor?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The seed implies a certain stored potential/dynamicism. Something ready to burst.
It implies the birth of something, anything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To trace the origin, to know what lies at the start of it all&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is our fascination with reaction, and sequence. To truly pinpoint how or why, the order of being. But most crucially, the acquiescence, the mother of being&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Baked into the definition/the core programming of the seed, is improbability. The terrifying beauty of uncertainty. What becomes of the seed, when it sprouts its germ?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seed, root, at the center, the start of the something. A seed, from which something blossoms. Seed of destruction, or the seed of a metaphorical flower&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>nzge</name></author><summary type="html">Why is the seed such a powerful metaphor?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Is the world healing</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/04/27/Is-the-world-healing.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Is the world healing" /><published>2025-04-27T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2025-04-27T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/04/27/Is%20the%20world%20healing</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/04/27/Is-the-world-healing.html">&lt;p&gt;Is the world finally healing?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a sense of liveliness and wonder again in the world. Or maybe it’s that I have changed.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>nzge</name></author><summary type="html">Is the world finally healing?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Questions</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/04/25/Questions.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Questions" /><published>2025-04-25T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2025-04-25T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/04/25/Questions</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/04/25/Questions.html">&lt;p&gt;Why do I frame everything in life as a question, and what does that say about who I am?
Today I attempt to uncover that secret? That secret.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I noticed that I like to put everything as a rhetorical, as an inquisition.
Maybe this is me placing a level of uncertainty on everything I understand about the world.
Or it’s a progressive belief that there is nuance to the world at every turn, and that there is more to be learned and nothing is fully answered. To open up the world to possibility and discovery is to the choice to live in a world of optimism. There is more to learn about the world, and thus life has meaning. 
There seems to be a correlation between true meaning in the world and the ability to inquire. Inquisition brings out meaning in the world. If there are more things to learn about that must mean there is meaning.
But why is that? Why is it that the perpetual search for understanding sparks a kind of significance to existence? Why is that what we don’t know brings a certain truth that there substance. Almost paradoxically, the absence of understanding brings about the presence of materiality/substance.
 When this concept is spoken, the idea resonates with me. But to fully understand why that is requires a deeper level of introspection that I am not certain I am capable of.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>nzge</name></author><summary type="html">Why do I frame everything in life as a question, and what does that say about who I am? Today I attempt to uncover that secret? That secret.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Positivity</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/04/23/Positivity.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Positivity" /><published>2025-04-23T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2025-04-23T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/04/23/Positivity</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/04/23/Positivity.html">&lt;p&gt;Having a positive outlook on any given situation is the only way to persist. It is the utilitarian approach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s as if positivity and faith is wired into our neural circuitry, our behavorial/subsistence mechanisms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is obviously a clear distinction between thriving and survival. Caveman ape people of the past were certainly not koombayah-ing in the imminent threat of a bear mauling the entire village. But who really knows what they were really thinking. The evolutionary perspective that got them out of pure survival surely most have involved some kind of positive outlook, where positivity is defined by a long term belief that holistically, our day-to-day life follows an upward trajectory, maybe not by some quantifiable metric but in the general sense. The cavemen may not have been scientific thinkers measuring their progress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The adoption of a positive mindset is when we begin to live as beings on this earth.
To be a cynic as the core is to claim defeat at the foot of death. A surrendering of our being.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>nzge</name></author><summary type="html">Having a positive outlook on any given situation is the only way to persist. It is the utilitarian approach.</summary></entry></feed>