<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-05-01T22:36:33-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">My Website</title><subtitle>my personal website</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Design</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/05/01/Design.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Design" /><published>2025-05-01T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2025-05-01T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/05/01/Design</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/05/01/Design.html">&lt;p&gt;For most people, design is overlooked. 
But in fact, it shapes the world we live in. 
Design carries a utiliarian/functionalist aspect. But it there is an aesthetic element.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The wooden veneer has become almost a cultural staple of the late 20th century to early 21st century aesthetic. There are these small yet resoundingly poignant details that shape the visual image of the world we live in today. These small little aesthetic metas ideas that persist and propagate, covering the entire visual landscape of a nation or world.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>nzge</name></author><summary type="html">For most people, design is overlooked. But in fact, it shapes the world we live in. Design carries a utiliarian/functionalist aspect. But it there is an aesthetic element.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Creative spill</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/04/30/Creative-Spill.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Creative spill" /><published>2025-04-30T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2025-04-30T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/04/30/Creative%20Spill</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/04/30/Creative-Spill.html">&lt;p&gt;What is “creative spill” and how do we harness it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes the flow is torrential. Sometimes it’s dry as a desert.
Creation is my therapy. 
Embrace the insanity, when you are in the zone and you want to do nothing else but the task at hand. Embrace the hyperfixation.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>nzge</name></author><summary type="html">What is “creative spill” and how do we harness it?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Questions</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/04/25/Questions.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Questions" /><published>2025-04-25T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2025-04-25T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/04/25/Questions</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/04/25/Questions.html">&lt;p&gt;Why do I frame everything in life as a question, and what does that say about who I am?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I noticed that I like to put everything as a rhetorical, as an inquisition.
Maybe this is me placing a level of uncertainty on everything I understand about the world.
Or it’s a progressive belief that there is nuance to the world at every turn, and that there is more to be learned and nothing is fully answered. To open up the world to possibility and discovery is to the choice to live in a world of optimism. There is more to learn about the world, and thus life has meaning. 
There seems to be a correlation between true meaning in the world and the ability to inquire. Inquisition brings out meaning in the world. If there are more things to learn about that must mean there is meaning.
But why is that? Why is it that the perpetual search for understanding sparks a kind of significance to existence? Why is that what we don’t know brings a certain truth that there substance. Almost paradoxically, the absence of understanding brings about the presence of materiality/substance.
 When this concept is spoken, the idea resonates with me. But to fully understand why that is requires a deeper level of introspection that I am not certain I am capable of.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>nzge</name></author><summary type="html">Why do I frame everything in life as a question, and what does that say about who I am?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Identity</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/04/20/Identity.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Identity" /><published>2025-04-20T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2025-04-20T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/04/20/Identity</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/04/20/Identity.html">&lt;p&gt;Why is it that at the genesis of any creation, the creation retains individuality/identity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Humans feel the need to normalize, flatten, and smooth. Turn everything into plain white bread. The birth of the internet everyone had their own corner of the web. Webrings, geocities, personal flair. Your own corner of the internet is customized. 
In basketball, old school players had a set of skills that shaped their identity as a player. Modern NBA, everyone is slowly starting to become the same player. Everyone posseses the same bag of tricks.
The same phenomenon exists in social media. Things like myspace and old youtube pages allowed you to customize the look of your page. Nowaways customization is stripped, everything is clean, minimal. The absence of character is loud and apparent.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>nzge</name></author><summary type="html">Why is it that at the genesis of any creation, the creation retains individuality/identity.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Normality</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/04/16/Normality.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Normality" /><published>2025-04-16T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2025-04-16T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/04/16/Normality</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/04/16/Normality.html">&lt;p&gt;Normalize uniqueness. Normalize doing things nobody has done, or doing things that you do not because you’ve seen someone else do them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We often seek a model/blueprint for action. That is what inhibits our natural potential. 
I look on social media, and sometimes feels like I’m looking into a sea of mindless pigs. Not quirky or interesting. We impress on ourselves a vision of social normality to not step out of place, under the notion that anything outside the norm is peculiar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Break the mold. Unironically we need to escape the matrix. Not in a alpha male Andrew Tate way, but trust our unique creative inhibitions to do things that ignite the human soul. This thought comes fresh off of listening to the riveting tales of Tim Sweeney, founder of Epic games and creator of Unreal engine. In the early days of the internet, it felt like every project became a breakthrough, because it was, and it had to be. Boundaries were pushed and new territory explored. It was normal. The passion from these developers was fueled by a lack of inhibition, to explore ideas coming purely from the mind unperturbed by what others may think. x&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>nzge</name></author><summary type="html">Normalize uniqueness. Normalize doing things nobody has done, or doing things that you do not because you’ve seen someone else do them.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Inspiration</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/04/15/Inspiration.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Inspiration" /><published>2025-04-15T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2025-04-15T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/04/15/Inspiration</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/04/15/Inspiration.html">&lt;p&gt;What inspires me?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is inspiration? Is it what drives us in our day to day action?
Is it what gets us out of bed?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Behind discipline (the moments where ) is there an underlying passion that drives our personal narrative. 
I have never found discipline to get me thorugh the day. If there is an action that I know to be good for me but I can’t convince myself on a spiritual level that it fundamentally contributes positively to who I am as a person, it is extremely hard for me to do it. I’m sure that isn’t an original thought. Maybe my understanding of discipline is completely miscontrued. 
But I always hear the most disciplined and successful people in the world, the David Goggins of the world, throw around the word/concept discipline as if this singular concept is what should drive us to perform the actions that we take. In my opinion the idea that that is what keeps us going is a bit reductive.
But at the same time, maybe life is not that complicated. We need simple words and concepts like “discipline” to drive us and push us. It is easy for our monkey brains to compute. A simple platitude to keep us from going insane.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>nzge</name></author><summary type="html">What inspires me?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Thoughts</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/04/13/Thoughts.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Thoughts" /><published>2025-04-13T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2025-04-13T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/04/13/Thoughts</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/04/13/Thoughts.html">&lt;p&gt;What ideas do I subscribe to? 
What is the meaning of life?&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>nzge</name></author><summary type="html">What ideas do I subscribe to? What is the meaning of life?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The internet is my teacher</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/04/12/The-Internet-is-my-Teacher.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The internet is my teacher" /><published>2025-04-12T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2025-04-12T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/04/12/The%20Internet%20is%20my%20Teacher</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/04/12/The-Internet-is-my-Teacher.html">&lt;p&gt;The internet is my greatest teacher and mentor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As sad as that may be, it’s true.
The breadth and depth of knowledge that the internet has provided to me has been insurmountable.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>nzge</name></author><summary type="html">The internet is my greatest teacher and mentor.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Open source</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/04/10/Open-Source.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Open source" /><published>2025-04-10T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2025-04-10T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/04/10/Open%20Source</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/04/10/Open-Source.html">&lt;p&gt;We stand on the backs of giants. Or maybe one metaphorical giant rather.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many current tools scrape/aggregate resources from across the web. Most egregious instances of this at the forefront of media are the various AI tools we use now on a daily basis.
Is this forgery/thievery or the next step in human evolution? That we as a singular race can levy the intellect of the entire human race, as one breathing unit? Open source on a global scale?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The power of open source as all-encompassing design/intellectual philosophy is one that favors an open collaboration with the world at large. An unselfish passing of information and material that doesn’t ask for any favors in return.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Does this promote homogeneity? The loss of self identity?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is solipsism the antithesis of this ideology? 
Does there exist a leech that only takes from the world but does not give?&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>nzge</name></author><summary type="html">We stand on the backs of giants. Or maybe one metaphorical giant rather.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">First post</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/04/09/First-Post.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="First post" /><published>2025-04-09T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2025-04-09T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/04/09/First%20Post</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/04/09/First-Post.html">&lt;p&gt;Hi. This is my first post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hello World.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;meep meep meep&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>nzge</name></author><summary type="html">Hi. This is my first post.</summary></entry></feed>